<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Chat With Chin</title>
    <link href="https://chatwithchin.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://chatwithchin.com" />
    <updated>2024-05-02T08:18:51-04:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Dr. Chinue Uecker</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chatwithchin.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Social and Governance Justice – the Influence and Role of Strategy and Strategists</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dr. Chinue Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://chatwithchin.com/social-and-governance-justice-the-influence-and-role-of-strategy-and-strategists.html"/>
        <id>https://chatwithchin.com/social-and-governance-justice-the-influence-and-role-of-strategy-and-strategists.html</id>

        <updated>2024-05-02T08:18:51-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    How does one celebrate the life of Ruth Bader Ginsburg? Let's start by realizing she was an icon for us all. Her unmistakable talent for building consensus using her intellect, skills, and voice has left a lasting imprint on our society. Whether you choose to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>How does one celebrate the life of Ruth Bader Ginsburg? Let's start by realizing she was an icon for us all. Her unmistakable talent for building consensus using her intellect, skills, and voice has left a lasting imprint on our society. Whether you choose to remember her as the "Notorious RBG" or "You can spell Truth without Ruth," one thing is for sure, she was a strategist. <a href="https://www.strategyassociation.org/?ref=chatwithchin.com">Strategy</a> resembles leadership. It is not a title, but a way of thinking to bring about bold action leading to transformation. With each step of her journey, she enacted change, developed those around her, and endeavored for liberty, equality, and progress. Now, what's next? As Ruth demonstrated perseverance and determination, let's do the same. Let's use our intellect. Let's use our skills. Let's use our voice. As strategists, let's bring bold action for change in our families, community, and organizations.</p>
<p>Original post: <a href="https://cdn.ymaws.com/www.strategyassociation.org/resource/resmgr/strategic_edge_newsletter_december_2015/2020/Updated__-_Social_and_Govern.pdf?ref=chatwithchin.com">Association for Strategic Planning - Strategic Edge October 2020</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Steps Toward Operational Excellence</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dr. Chinue Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://chatwithchin.com/steps-toward-operational-excellence.html"/>
        <id>https://chatwithchin.com/steps-toward-operational-excellence.html</id>

        <updated>2024-05-02T08:18:08-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Operational Excellence is a workplace philosophy that embraces problem-solving, teamwork, and leadership to create sustainable improvement and growth. The process involves focusing on the customers' needs, keeping the employees positive and empowered, and continually improving the current activities in the workplace. Why is Operational Excellence essential&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><a href="https://www.industryweek.com/leadership/companies-executives/article/21974583/operational-excellence-defined?ref=chatwithchin.com">Operational Excellence</a> is a workplace philosophy that embraces problem-solving, teamwork, and leadership to create sustainable improvement and growth. The process involves focusing on the customers' needs, keeping the employees positive and empowered, and continually improving the current activities in the workplace.</p>
<p>Why is Operational Excellence essential within healthcare? It not only enables each employee, regardless of function, to see and understand various patient pathways within the healthcare setting; it also empowers employees to resolve problems when they arise. There are many tools and techniques that can be used to help organizations along their journey to Operational Excellence.  The <a href="https://asq.org/quality-resources/lean/value-stream-mapping?ref=chatwithchin.com">Value Stream Map</a> is one of the more leveraged tools as it helps the team see the flow, identify waste, and analyze data relevant to the organization. With that visual in place, teams can explore different areas using detailed <a href="https://asq.org/quality-resources/flowchart?ref=chatwithchin.com">Process Maps</a> to show sequential steps by function or <a href="https://asq.org/quality-resources/spaghetti-diagram?ref=chatwithchin.com">Spaghetti Diagrams </a>to visualize the movement of patients, staff, or materials. Data collection also plays a key role in this process and when combined with the use of methods like <a href="https://www.mindtools.com/pages/article/newTMC_5W.htm?ref=chatwithchin.com">5 Whys</a> and Cause and Effect Diagrams (also known as <a href="https://asq.org/quality-resources/fishbone?ref=chatwithchin.com">Fishbone or Ishikawa diagrams</a>), teams can begin to understand the root cause of problems or identify waste.</p>
<p>Healthcare leaders are instrumental in ensuring resources are available to improve quality, access, satisfaction, and cost. With strategically focused improvement events, organizations can transform how care is delivered by working toward providing lower cost, better quality, and easy access for patients.</p>
<p>As with any change, improvement teams truly benefit when patients, caregivers, and those who perform the work feel empowered and are involved in the engagement. Improvement events can utilize <a href="http://r20.rs6.net/tn.jsp?f=001bJGwetpOB6YaDCdiOPDze8ZI0SOLc69jI2Gt4bW4FwxtNlttbystO1HVTI3cMuL1bwQ1Gd_vWl41w8r5oDOR7rXaPizMpzjqiq0dry9EB53ujmBlHa63NNALUT6zygeMq-ylRS9K96zgv7_F3XAUThPwXm4_4uca-JkoMHInOXg3Zh1NEaJjN9Xr2d3R-996zr7nVk1Aj30opTrmtDhLv3WJiLe1RifYVIy_X6oQIu4%3D&amp;c=gpdol0ZBYuncoHn4GeLXYIsuZWo_KeMxJKtcHtACM9EnSRyZPRFhvQ%3D%3D&amp;ch=Ilm32OfeJwdKEEeW8OyHtWa_P1323Gi9quDWERgIOiy_xdGtvr0CjQ%3D%3D&amp;ref=chatwithchin.com" rel="noopener noreferrer">A3 Thinking</a>, <a href="https://asq.org/quality-resources/pdca-cycle?ref=chatwithchin.com">PDCA/PDSA</a>, <a href="https://www.mindtools.com/pages/article/newSTR_97.htm?ref=chatwithchin.com">Kaizen</a>, or <a href="https://goleansixsigma.com/lean-six-sigma/?ref=chatwithchin.com">Lean/Six Sigma</a> methodology. While ultimately, patient satisfaction improves, so does employee satisfaction through efficiency and productivity gains.</p>
<p>To ensure that changes are sustained, project teams can create control plans along with standard work. The control plan and standard work provides clear information for teams to follow. In addition, teams should document lessons learned and celebrate their efforts to improve patient care.</p>
<p>Original post: <a href="https://www.renayejames.com/?ref=chatwithchin.com">Renaye James Healthcare Advisors</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>From Hungar to Housing to Employment in Rural Communities</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dr. Chinue Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://chatwithchin.com/from-hungar-to-housing-to-employment-in-rural-communities.html"/>
        <id>https://chatwithchin.com/from-hungar-to-housing-to-employment-in-rural-communities.html</id>

        <updated>2024-05-02T08:17:37-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    As rural communities prepare to distribute the vaccine, many towns are grappling with challenges like employment, housing, and hunger exacerbated by the pandemic. These challenges are intertwined. To combat these challenges, rural leaders believe that keeping individuals housed safely, providing mobile food pantries to improve&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>As rural communities prepare to distribute the vaccine, many towns are grappling with challenges like employment, housing, and hunger exacerbated by the pandemic. These challenges are intertwined. To combat these challenges, rural leaders believe that keeping individuals housed safely, providing mobile food pantries to improve access to fresh foods, and partnering with local businesses to innovate local economies are a few approaches rural communities could utilize. Why is it so important to tap into rural residents, business owners, and officials' collective knowledge? Rural communities need to be engaged in the process from the start to identify viable solutions and sustain improvements made.</p>
<p>To learn more, read <a href="https://www.naco.org/articles/lucc-rac-members-talk-housing-hunger-pandemic-continues?ref=chatwithchin.com">LUCC, RAC members talk housing, hunger as pandemic continues</a>.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Innovations in Care</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dr. Chinue Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://chatwithchin.com/innovations-in-care.html"/>
        <id>https://chatwithchin.com/innovations-in-care.html</id>

        <updated>2024-05-02T08:16:31-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    1.1 million. 400,000. 135,000. Those numbers represent the Los Angeles Fire Department's sole efforts in 2019 to address 1.1 million calls, attend to 400,000 incidents, and treat 135,000 patients on scene. You may be asking yourself, amid COVID-19, how can providers adjust the traditional care&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>1.1 million. 400,000. 135,000. Those numbers represent the Los Angeles Fire Department's sole efforts in 2019 to address 1.1 million calls, attend to 400,000 incidents, and treat 135,000 patients on scene.  You may be asking yourself, amid COVID-19, how can providers adjust the traditional care models to innovate and provide the right care and the right time? A Mobile Integrated Health Care strategy is an example of an innovative partnership between Los Angeles's 911 Emergency Medical Services and local health care leaders to leverage people, process, and technology using telehealth and prehospital patient navigation.</p>
<p>To learn more, read the full article on <a href="https://catalyst.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/CAT.20.0383?query=EDP&amp;cid=DM109754_Catalyst_Non_Subscriber&amp;bid=370778991&amp;ref=chatwithchin.com">NEJM Catalyst Innovations in Care Delivery</a>.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
